Main Menu

Privacy Policy
==============

(_Last Updated on April 2, 2024_; _Version 2024/1.0_)

Your privacy is important to us. Therefore, we are committed to respecting Your privacy and the confidentiality of Your personal data and content. This Privacy Policy is designed to assist You in understanding how BasisTech LLC (“BasisTech,” “We,” “Our” or “Us”) uses and safeguards the information You provide in the course of purchasing and/or using BasisTech products, services and websites (the “Services”).

This document (“Privacy Policy”) describes Our policies concerning the use of personal information of users collected during the course of providing the Services as in effect from the date last updated, as set forth above.

We reserve the right, in Our discretion, to change, modify and delete provisions of this Privacy Policy at any time. If we do change how we use personally identifiable information (or make other changes to this Privacy Policy), we will post the changes on this page or email You a notice, in each case indicating the effective date, so that You are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Your continued use of any of the Services after such notice constitutes Your acceptance of the modified Privacy Policy.

### What information do we collect?

In order to provide You with access to the Services, we may gather and process some or all of the following information:

* **Content**: any information that is submitted, stored or collected by or from users of the Services, other than Reviews and Comments, Registration Information, Customer Service Communications or Log Information.
* **Reviews and Comments**: information that is voluntarily provided by a user of the Services (such as questions and comments posted to the User Forum) intended for public disclosure, regarding the use of the applicable Service or the features provided by the applicable Service.
* **Registration Information**: any information provided when purchasing a license for, or voluntarily registering for use of a Service, and any information provided when requesting information about a Service or indicating interest in receiving information about a Service, including, but not limited to, first and last names, username and password, postal address, email address, phone number, employer, job title, and billing information.
* **Customer Service Communications**: any information that is reported to us about the operation of the Services, or in the context of a Support Services request, including bug reports or requests for enhancements.
* **Log Information**: When You use certain Services, Our servers, or those of Our third-party vendors, may automatically record basic information such as Your Internet Protocol address, other addressing information, the date and time of Your request and an authentication token used to validate the identity of You and Your computer.

### Age Limitation

The Services are not directed to persons under the age of 18. If You become aware that Your child has provided us with personal information without Your consent, please contact us at [privacy@basistech.com](mailto:privacy@basistech.com). We do not knowingly collect or solicit information from, market to or provide services to persons under 18 years old. If we become aware that a person under 18 has provided us with personal information, we take steps to remove such information and, if applicable, terminate the person’s account.

### How do we use this information and for what purpose?

Our primary purposes in collecting information are to communicate with you in relation to Services you have requested from us, and to provide You with an efficient user experience in relation to those Services.  We may use the information that we collect to: provide the Services and any customer support You request; resolve disputes, collect fees, and troubleshoot problems; enforce applicable Terms of Use, license agreements and other agreed terms and conditions related to the Services; customize, measure, and improve the Services, inform You about service updates, and other products, services, and promotional offers available from BasisTech; compare information for accuracy, and verify Your identity; provide other services for You as described when we collect the information.

We use Customer Service Communications to improve and support the Services. You may voluntarily provide suggestions, comments or other feedback to us with respect to Services or other items or information provided by Us with respect thereto. This Information is used for the purposes of reviewing this feedback and improving the Services. We are not required to hold such feedback in confidence, and such feedback may be used by us for any purpose without obligation of any kind.  We reserve the right to utilize anonymous information for marketing purposes, for instance by displaying selected comments on the Services or in other communications or fora.  Further, we may from time to time ask You to provide information on Your experiences which will be used to measure and improve quality.  You are at no time under any obligation to provide any such data.

We will use Log Information to provide You with access to the Services and for statistical information.

If You are using one of the Services for Your business application, You are responsible for the use and privacy of Your users’ Content.

We may also use Your information as described below and in our KonaSearch Privacy Policy located at [https://www.konasearch.com/privacy-policy/](https://www.konasearch.com/privacy-policy/?__hstc=51627318.6c10002cfdd458d1289ff32af679d0e6.1689941031016.1707874165449.1707924169641.47&__hssc=51627318.16.1707924169641&__hsfp=435398809).

**REGISTRATION INFORMATION**

We ask for Registration Information in order to verify Your identity and to enable Your use of the Services.  We use third party vendors to host and manage Our API management and log-in processes, Our accounts and marketing systems, and for billing services.  Your Registration Information, including billing data, is stored by these vendors, and We have access to this information through Our vendor accounts.  We rely on the protection measures and certifications offered by these vendors to protect Your Registration Information. Upon written request, BasisTech will provide You with the names of these vendors.

We respect the privacy of personal e-mail accounts and will restrict access to Your e-mail addresses (within Our applicable vendor accounts) to those who have a need to know for the purposes permitted in this Privacy Policy.  We will not send You unwanted e-mail messages or junk mail, and Your details will not be passed to third parties for their marketing purposes without Your explicit permission.  However, we will use e-mail to send You messages about faults and service issues.  We may also use e-mail to keep You up to date with news about the Services.

If You do not want to be kept informed in this way by e-mail, please contact us at [support@basistech.com](mailto:support@basistech.com).  Further, we reserve the right to use e-mail to notify You of any claims related to Your use of the Services, including without limitation claims of violation of third party rights.

**CONTENT**

Your Content is processed through virtual machines hosted via Amazon Web Services (“AWS”). BasisTech relies on the data protection measures and certification offered by AWS to protect Your Content. In general, except for access by AWS, and except as disclosed in the applicable agreements, we will not use, review or provide third parties access to Your Content except as specifically authorized by You.  In particular, Our AWS hosted virtual machines normally process the Content submitted by an Authorized User and return the results of Our processing to the Authorized User that submitted the Content. We do not retain any of Your Content after it has been processed. However, if required by law, we reserve the right to pre-screen, review, flag, filter, modify, refuse or remove any or all Content from the Services.

We will also collect and use metadata related to Your use of the Services, such as anonymized Content and account metrics based on or generated by (i) Your use of the Services and/or (ii) Your Content (“Metadata”). Metadata will be used to generate anonymized and aggregated reports for analysis purposes. These reports will not contain personally identifiable information.

**REVIEWS AND COMMENTS**

We use Reviews and Comments, such as comments posted on Our users’ forum, for the purpose of providing content to other users of Our sites, and for improving Our products and services.  In addition, we have the right to use, reproduce, modify, adapt, publish, perform, translate, create derivative works from, distribute, and display Reviews and Comments throughout the world in any media. However, if required by law, we reserve the right to pre-screen, review, flag, filter, modify, refuse or remove any or all Reviews and Comments from Our sites.

### To whom do we transfer Your personal information?

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, we do not sell, rent, trade or otherwise transfer any Registration Information or Content to any third party without Your explicit permission, unless we are obliged to do so under applicable laws or by order of the competent authorities. As noted above, if You are using one of the Services via a third party application provider (“Application Provider”), the Application Provider will normally have the right to control the transfer of information You provide via the applicable application.

We may share Your information with Our affiliates and other service providers that We utilize to provide the Services. As noted above, when registering for one of the Services, You may provide Your Registration Information directly to one of Our service providers, who may send us, or provide access to that information in order for Us to operate the applicable Service.   We may also offer some of Our Services in connection with other service providers.  Registration Information that You provide to us may be sent to those providers in order to deliver the service provided by them; similarly, personal information that You provide to those sites may be sent to us in order to operate the Services.

BasisTech may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your Registration Information may be transferred to the external business partner. BasisTech may share data with trusted partners to help perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to BasisTech, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Information collected by us may be stored and processed in any country in which We, Our affiliates, and Our third party service providers maintain facilities.  We reserve the right to transfer information outside of the country where You reside and/or from which You use the Services.  By using one of the Services You consent to any such transfer of information.

As we continue to develop Our business, we may sell or buy subsidiaries or business units. In such transactions as well as in the event all or some of Our assets are acquired by a third party, personal information of Our users will generally be one of the transferred business assets. We reserve the right to include Your personal information, collected as an asset, in any such transfer to a third party.

Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this Privacy Policy, or in the Master Services Agreement, End User License Agreement, or any other agreement applicable to any Services, we may access, use, preserve or disclose any information we have access to if we have a good faith belief that such access, use, preservation or disclosure of any information is reasonably necessary to (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request, (b) enforce the terms of our agreements with You, including investigation of potential violations thereof, (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or (d) protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of us, Our users or the public as required or permitted by law.

### How do we protect Your personal information?

As noted above, Your Registration Information and Content are stored by, and processed by virtual machines hosted by Our third party vendors. We rely on the data protection measures and certifications offered by these third party vendors. We also take other appropriate organizational and technical measures to protect the data provided to us or collected by us, and do not retain it any longer than permitted in order to provide the Services or as required under relevant legislation, with due observance of the applicable obligations and exceptions under the relevant legislation.  You should be aware that internet communications are not always secure.  Although we or Our third party vendors do take what we consider appropriate steps to protect Your data, protection of information available over the internet is subject to attack from third parties, and accordingly we cannot promise You that third parties cannot access the information You provide when you use the Services.

In this regard, where applicable to the Service you are accessing, You are responsible for maintaining the security and confidentiality of Your account passwords and Your API Key.  It is a condition of Your use that You agree we are not liable for any such disclosure. The security of Your account relies on Your protection of Your password and Your API Key. You are solely responsible for any and all activities that occur under Your account. You may not share Your password with anyone. We will never ask You to send Your password or other sensitive information to us in an email, although we may ask You to enter this type of information on our sites. Any email or other communication requesting Your password, asking You to provide sensitive account information via email, or linking to a website with a URL that does not begin with http://www.basistech should be treated as unauthorized and suspicious and should be reported to Us immediately at support@basistech.com. If You do share Your password with a third party for any reason, the third party will have access to Your account and Your personal information, and You may be responsible for actions taken using Your password.

If You believe someone else has obtained access to Your password, please change it immediately by logging in to Your account and changing Your account settings. If You believe that an unauthorized access has already occurred please report it immediately to support@basistech.com.

### What rights do You have and how can You contact us?

If you use Our products or services, You can review and modify most of Your personal information at any time by accessing Your account.  When Your account is closed, or upon Your request, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to remove Your personal information from our sites, although removed information may persist in backup or archived copies.

If You would like to exercise Your right to view, correct, complete or remove Your personal data, please contact us at [privacy@basistech.com](mailto:privacy@basistech.com). Upon verification of Your identity, we will attempt to quickly fulfill Your request, provided we will not act contrary to applicable legislation.

### How long is Your personal data kept by us?

We will retain Your information for as long as is necessary or permitted to: (1) provide the Services; (2) invoice You for use of the Services and maintain records until invoicing for the Services cannot be lawfully challenged; (3) communicate with You regarding other services that we offer; (4) comply with applicable legislation, regulatory requests and relevant orders from competent courts; (5) enforce Our Terms of Use and/or license agreements applicable to the Services; or (6) fulfill any of the other purposes detailed in this Privacy Policy.

### What are cookies and how do we use them?

We and Our third party vendors use cookies and log files to administer the Site. A log file is a list of recent actions that is maintained by Our servers (or those of Our third party vendors). A cookie is a piece of data that we (or Our third party vendors) store on Your hard drive and that may contain information about You and Your computer. This promotes ease of communication between Your computer and the Site and enables us to improve the user experience, for example to take a user back to a page to which the user has previously navigated. (You may be able to use Your computer’s control panel to disable cookies; but doing so may affect Your ease in using the Site.)

Some of Our business partners may use cookies on Our Service.  However, we have no access to or control over any cookies that may be used by linked or other third party sites.

### How far does Our responsibility extend?

Our Services may contain links to third party web sites and may redirect You to third party web sites (“Third Party Sites”). These Third Party Sites may include, among others, service providers who have a relationship with us. Third Party Sites are not under Our control, and we are not responsible for such Third Party Sites, including without limitation the accuracy, sufficiency, correctness, reliability, veracity, completeness, or timeliness thereof, any link contained therein, or any changes or updates thereto. The inclusion or access to Third Party Sites does not imply an endorsement thereof by us or of the provider of such content or service, or of any third party web site. We reserve the right to terminate any link or linking program at any time. Please be aware that when You enter a Third Party Site, any information You provide, including financial information, is subject to the terms of use and privacy policy of that Third Party Site.

### Can this Privacy Policy be modified?

We reserve the right to modify the provisions of this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will inform You of these changes by publishing the revised Privacy Policy at [https://www.basistech.com/privacy-policy](https://www.basistech.com/privacy-policy).  You agree that the express acceptance by You or Your continued use of the Services shall constitute Your acceptance of the Privacy Policy.

### Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers who are California residents and who have provided the Company with “personal information” (as that term is defined in Section 1798.83) to request certain information about the disclosure of that information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. If You are a California resident with questions regarding this, please contact us at [privacy@basistech.com](mailto:privacy@basistech.com) or at BasisTech LLC, 1070 Broadway, Somerville, MA, 02144.

1070 Broadway  
Somerville, MA 02144-2078

617-386-2000  

* ©2024 BasisTech. All Rights Reserved.
